<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CV | Ruiming&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://rmcao.github.io/tag/cv/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://rmcao.github.io/tag/cv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CV</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Ruiming Cao | Website icon from openmoji.org</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:54:48 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://rmcao.github.io/images/icon_hucd15fd8e38fe1904d624914b135f094f_55420_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://rmcao.github.io/tag/cv/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting CNN Knowledge via an Explanatory Graph</title>
      <link>https://rmcao.github.io/project/explanatorygraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:54:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmcao.github.io/project/explanatorygraph/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Object Parts from CNNs via Active Question-Answering</title>
      <link>https://rmcao.github.io/project/growingpartgraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 12:37:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmcao.github.io/project/growingpartgraph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given a convolutional neural network (CNN) that is pre-trained for object classification, this paper proposes to use active question-answering to semanticize neural patterns in conv-layers of the CNN and mine part concepts. For each part concept, we mine neural patterns in the pre-trained CNN, which are related to the target part, and use these patterns to construct an And-Or graph (AOG) to represent a four-layer semantic hierarchy of the part. As an interpretable model, the AOG associates different CNN units with different explicit object parts. We use an active human-computer communication to incrementally grow such an AOG on the pre-trained CNN as follows. We allow the computer to actively identify objects, whose neural patterns cannot be explained by the current AOG. Then, the computer asks human about the unexplained objects, and uses the answers to automatically discover certain CNN patterns corresponding to the missing knowledge. We incrementally grow the AOG to encode new knowledge discovered during the active-learning process. In experiments, our method exhibits high learning efficiency. Our method uses about 1/6-1/3 of the part annotations for training, but achieves similar or better part-localization performance than fast-RCNN methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
