<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CI | Ruiming&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://rmcao.github.io/tag/ci/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://rmcao.github.io/tag/ci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CI</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Ruiming Cao | Website icon from openmoji.org</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 13:55:37 -0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://rmcao.github.io/images/icon_hucd15fd8e38fe1904d624914b135f094f_55420_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>CI</title>
      <link>https://rmcao.github.io/tag/ci/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Structured Illumination Microscopy with a Neural Space-time Model</title>
      <link>https://rmcao.github.io/project/speckleflowsim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 13:55:37 -0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmcao.github.io/project/speckleflowsim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Structured illumination microscopy (SIM) reconstructs a super-resolved image from multiple raw images captured with different illumination patterns; hence, acquisition speed is limited, making it unsuitable for dynamic scenes. We propose a new method, Speckle Flow SIM, that uses static patterned illumination with moving samples and models the sample motion during data capture in order to reconstruct the dynamic scene with super-resolution. Speckle Flow SIM relies on sample motion to capture a sequence of raw images. The spatio-temporal relationship of the dynamic scene is modeled using a neural space-time model with coordinate-based multi-layer perceptrons (MLPs), and the motion dynamics and the super-resolved scene are jointly recovered. We validate Speckle Flow SIM for coherent imaging in simulation and build a simple, inexpensive experimental setup with off-the-shelf components. We demonstrate that Speckle Flow SIM can reconstruct a dynamic scene with deformable motion and 1.88x the diffraction-limited resolution in experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{cao2022dynamic,
  title={Dynamic Structured Illumination Microscopy with a Neural Space-time Model},
  author={Cao, Ruiming and Liu, Fanglin Linda and Yeh, Li-Hao and Waller, Laura},
  journal={arXiv preprint arXiv:2206.01397},
  year={2022}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-calibrated 3D differential phase contrast microscopy with optimized illumination</title>
      <link>https://rmcao.github.io/project/motion3ddpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 12:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmcao.github.io/project/motion3ddpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3D phase imaging recovers an object’s volumetric refractive index from intensity and/or holographic measurements. Partially coherent methods, such as illumination-based differential phase contrast (DPC), are particularly simple to implement in a commercial brightfield microscope. 3D DPC acquires images at multiple focus positions and with different illumination source patterns in order to reconstruct 3D refractive index. Here, we present a practical extension of the 3D DPC method that does not require a precise motion stage for scanning the focus and uses optimized illumination patterns for improved performance. The user scans the focus by hand, using the microscope’s focus knob, and the algorithm self-calibrates the axial position to solve for the 3D refractive index of the sample through a computational inverse problem. We further show that the illumination patterns can be optimized by an end-to-end learning procedure. Combining these two, we demonstrate improved 3D DPC with a commercial microscope whose only hardware modification is LED array illumination.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
